A Guide to the Preston Family (Charles Peale Didier Collection) Papers, 1747-1897
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Preston Family (Charles Peale Didier Collection) Papers,
1747-1897
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Preston, William, 1729-1783
Patton, James, 1692-1755 (Preston family, Montgomery County, Va.)
Preston, John, 1764-1827
Ms1985-020
1.5 Cubic Feet 3 boxes; 1 folder
The Didier Collection of Preston Family Papers includes papers of James Patton, Patton's grandson William Preston, and Preston's eldest son, John Preston, all of Montgomery County, Virginia. The papers consist of business and legal documents, surveys, and correspondence.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Preston Family (Charles Peale Didier Collection) Papers were donated to Special Collections in 1985. Additional materials were donated in March and April 1990. Later additions are denoted by folder numbers containing the letter "a."
Scope and Content
The Didier Collection of Preston Family Papers includes papers of James Patton, Patton's grandson William Preston, and Preston's eldest son, John Preston, all of Montgomery County, Virginia. The Preston family was important in the surveying, settlement, military affairs, and government of Southwest Virginia in the 18th and 19th centuries. Their papers consist of business and legal documents, surveys, and correspondence. Much of the collection relates to John Preston (1764-1827), treasurer of the Commonwealth of Virginia from 1810 to 1819. For further information on the Preston family, see John F. Dorman, The Prestons of Smithfield and Greenfield in Virginia (1982).
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in series by individual or family name. Within each series, materials are arranged chronologically with undated materials at the end.
Materials relating to James Patton are in Box 1, Folders 1-4. Those relating to William Preston (1729-83) are in Box 1, Folders 5-13. John Preston materials are in Box 2, Folders 1-39, and materials relating to members of his family in Box 2, Folders 40-41. Box 3 contains miscellaneous and unidentified papers. Wherever possible, materials are arranged chronologically.
Related Material
Special Collections has a number of other collections related to the Preston family, including:
Association for the Preservation of Virginia Antiquities, Montgomery County Branch Papers, 1754-1996. Ms62-001. Finding aid available online.
John Preston Deed, 1826. Ms2005-014.
John Preston Papers, 1806-1830, 1844, n.d. Ms1994-034. Finding aid available online.
Preston Family (Alice Preston Moore Collection) Papers, 1745-1882. Ms1962-004.
Robert Taylor Preston Papers, 1849-1871 (Bulk 1861-1862). Ms1992-003. Finding aid available online.
Smithfield Preston Foundation Papers, 1784-1881. Ms1997-002. Finding aid available online.
William Preston Land Grant, 1773. Ms1994-027.
Willard Preston Genealogy, c.1998. Ms2009-121. Finding aid available online.
George Green Shackelford Papers, 1899-1990 (Bulk 1955-1989). Ms1983-008. Finding aid available online.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; Women -- History; Montgomery County (Va.); Blacksburg (Va.)
Family Names:
Preston family (Montgomery County, Va.)
- James Patton Papers, 1747-1770
  - Survey of a property [belonging to Robert Norris?] for Col. James Patton and Company, March 2, 1747 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Promissory note of William Pepper to James Patton; Augusta County, February 18, 1753 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Promissory note of John M. Colley to James Patton et al., [August 24?] 1753 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Land indenture between James Patton and William Leppard for 75 acres in Augusta County (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Land indenture between James Patton and John Cal-breath for 61 acres in Augusta County (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Land indenture of James Patton for 193 acres in Augusta County; Augusta County, November 3, 17?? (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Judgments on James Patton's estate; Signed John Madison; Augusta County, November 1770 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Papers Relating to William Preston (1729-1783) and Family, 1755-1806
  - Received of Wm. Carravan, whiskey for the use of a company of patrollers; Signed Wm. Preston, July 23, 1755 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bill for goods bought by Wm. Preston; Signed Felix Gilbert, October 20, 1758 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - List of quit rents of the Middle District of Augusta. Shows accounts insolvent and paid, 1759-1760; Also includes arrears received by William Preston, 1755, 1756, 1757, and 1758; new patents, 1759; and new patents, 1760 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bond of John McNully and Andrew Greer to Wm. Preston, Sheriff of Augusta; Augusta County, January 31, 1760 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Received of Wm. Preston, payment for itemized goods; Signed David Cloyd, May 1760 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Land indenture between Tobias Smith and Wm. Preston for 330 acres in Augusta County "included in the Greenfield Tract;" Augusta County, May 12, 1760 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Promissory note for a sum to be paid to Messrs. Cranford and Simpson; Signed Wm. Preston, December 17, 1761 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Robt. Breckinridge to William Preston, a bill to be paid to James Lockart, May 25, 1762 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Promissory note for a sum to be paid to Robert McClenachan by Wm. Preston and Robert Breckinridge; Signed by Preston and Breckinridge; Augusta County, June 26, 1763 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Andrew Boyd [to William Preston?], requesting the transport of goods which arrived for Boyd from Scot-land; Fort Lewis, June 17, 1766 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Account of William Preston with Arch[ibald?] Buchanan containing itemized list of household goods, October 30, 1766 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Gabriel Jones to [William Preston?], reply to a letter; Concerns land sale accounts, November 30, 1767 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - John Todd to John Brown in Augusta, concerning a runaway wench Todd now wants to sell to Col. [William] Preston, July 5, 1768 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Received of Alexander Ingram a payment by Wm. Lush; Witnessed and signed by Wm. Preston, April 9, 1770 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bill to Joseph McMurtry on behalf of Thos. Eakins for survey of 120 acres land; Signed by McMurtry and Wm. Preston, September 24, 1770 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Promissory note for a sum to be paid to David Cloyd by William Preston and W. John Armstrong; Signed by Preston and Armstrong. Botetourt County, February 11, 1772 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Christiana Davies and Benjamin Coxley to Col. William Preston in Botetourt County; Refers to Andrew Lewis being appointed to executor of William Davies' estate; Philadelphia, July 17, 1772 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letter from G. Washington to William Preston (typescript transcript copy), February 24, 1774 (Box 1, Folder 11a)
  - Survey for Lazarus Benton of 116 acres in Fincastle County; Signed Robert Preston and Wm. Preston, December 12, 1774 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Received of William Preston a debt paid as executor of the estate of Col. John Buchanan; Signed James Crockett, August 1, 1774 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Account of William Madison with Jeremiah Pate, the balance to be paid to Wm. Preston as executor of James Patton. Signed Jeremiah Pate, October 25, 1781 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - William Preston to Henry Coleman, referring to ten dollars sent for "old Mr. Stapleton" and Preston's efforts to acquire a plough horse, March 1, 1783 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Promissory note, James P. Preston to Christian Martin, October 26, 1798 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Susanna Preston to Mr. Champ, requesting hemp, wheat, and corn, September 5, 1790 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Received from E. Madison, two plots of land surveyed by William Preston; Signed Jeremiah Patrick, July 22, 1792 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Note regarding hemp belonging to Capt. James Preston; Signed Robert Graham. Manchester, December 23, 1800 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Accounts for taxes paid by Nathaniel Hart for William Preston (deceased); Signed by Hart, 1802-1806 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- John Preston (1764-1827) Papers, 1780-1830, n.d.
  - Account for claims in Montgomery County to be paid by John Preston in surveyors' fees, March 20, 1780 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Memorandum of a land contract between John Smith and John Preston, April 11, 1784 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Joseph Cloyd to Capt. John Preston; Concerns a loan, September 3, 1784 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Request "to Mr. Preston" for registration of 129 acres of land for John Lawrence; Signed Richard Whitt, February 1786 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Record of land warrants recorded by Mary Smith for Henry Smith, received from John Preston by the hand of Robt. Preston; Russell County, November 16, 1786 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - James Beacon to John Preston in Montgomery County; Fragment; Williamsburg, March 16, 1787 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Col. Harvie to John Preston in Montgomery County; Requests information on a tract of land on the Kentucky River surveyed in William Preston's time, August 12, 1788 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Surveys of 8 pieces of property (on one sheet) in Montgomery County for various persons; Each signed J. Preston, 1780s (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Christley Pickle [to Capt. John Preston?]; Note withdrawing a land entry claim, April 23, 1790 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Deposition regarding land dealings of John and Francis Preston; Kanhawa County, May 14, 1790 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Alexander Breckenridge to John Preston at Smithfield, Montgomery County; Concerns a request for a loan; Beargrass, June 12, 1790 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Reuben Slaughter to John Preston in Montgomery County; Requests information on entries and rights of settlement for various properties; Greenbrier, September 9, 1790 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Certification that Wilson Ivy, a soldier in John Preston's company, is owed back pay; Signed J. Preston, September 27, 1792 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - William Preston to "Dear Brother," Captain John Preston, in Richmond; Refers to Gen. Wayne's march from Pittsburg, William's planned trip to Richmond; Prince Edward Courthouse, October 18, 1792 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Francis Preston to "Dear Brother," John Preston, in Montgomery County; Concerns land warrants and their proper registration; Saltworks, August 1, 1795 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Received of John Preston, taxes paid on James Patton's land in Montgomery County; Signed David Cloyd, November 2, 1795 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - J. McDowell to Col. John Preston in Richmond; Concerns a land survey by Preston; Mr. Miller has conditionally sold Preston's survey to Mr. Wolcott; Rockbridge, November 11, 1796 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Wm. Preston to "Dear Brother," Col. John Preston, in Montgomery County; Refers to orders requiring William to march his troops to Staunton, his planned trip to Rockbridge; Fincastle, September 25, 1797 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - John Breckenridge to Col. John Preston in Montgomery County; Concerns the collection of a debt owed to Breckenridge by a third party, October 23, 1798 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Wm. Radford to [his son-in-law] Gen. John Preston in Montgomery County; Refers to Radford's planned trip to Kentucky, the Napoleonic Wars in Europe; Richmond, June 6, 1799 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Gordon Cloyd to Gen. John Preston at Smithfield; Concerns land surveys at Horseshoe; Springfield, August 3, 1799 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Nathaniel Hart to Gen. John Preston in Montgomery County; Concerns a delay in Mr. Radford's law suit; Franklin, March 5, 1800 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Francis Preston to "Dear Brother," Gen. John Preston, in Montgomery County; Inquires about arrangements made regarding the Loyal Company's holdings after George Taylor's death, April 25, 1801 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Thos. L. Preston to "Dear Brother," Gen. John Preston, at Horshoe Bottom, Montgomery County; Refers to Thomas's journey to [William and Mary] College; Richmond, December 8, 1801 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Wm. Radford to [his son-in-law] Gen. John Preston at Horseshoe Bottom, in Montgomery County; Concerns family matters, April 12, 1802 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Henry L. Shore [to John Preston?]; Refers to Col. Vandewall executing a deed; the recovery of Martha and Carleton Radford; Richmond, July 27, 1802 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Charles Taylor to Gen. Preston at Horseshoe; Concerns the prospective marriage of Taylor's son to Preston's daughter, September 3, 1803 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Eliza Madison to "My Dear Brother," Gen. John Preston, in Montgomery County; Concerns her two horses being stolen and her efforts to recover them; farm matters; Dumfries, November 9, 1803 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Francis Preston to "Dear Brother," Gen. John Preston, in Richmond; Refers to Negroes going to Horseshoe and the possibility of hiring additional ones in Richmond; Talks of Kentucky's advantages and disadvantages, and a planned trip to the springs, December 28, 1803 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Wm. Preston to "Dear Brother," Gen. John Preston, at Horseshoe; Refers to breeding one of William's mares, plans for traveling to Smithfield, June 1, 1804 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - William Munford to Gen. John Preston at Horseshoe Bottom, Montgomery County; Refers to Napoleon Bonaparte's victories; family matters; land in Ohio; Richland, June 12, 1804 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - James McDowell to [his brother-in-law] Gen. John Preston in Montgomery County; Concerns land purchases from Mr. Brown, McDowell's travel plans to Ohio; Rockbridge, February 17, 1805 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Bowker Preston to Gen. John Preston in Montgomery County; Concerns brandy purchased from Preston by John Hook; Montgomery Court House, June 4, 1805 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Wm. Radford to [his brother-in-law] Gen. John Preston; Concerns Radford's course of study at Washington Academy and planned attendance at William and Mary; Washington Academy, August 1, 1805 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Thomas Preston to "Dear Brother," Gen. John Preston, at Horseshoe, Montgomery County; Concerns goods that Thomas was to purchase for his mother in Lexington and Richmond; Lexington, December 8, 1805 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - John Radford to [his brother-in-law] Gen. John at Horshoe Bottom, Montgomery County; Concerns land dealings in Chesmont County [Kentucky?]; Washington Township, Chesmont County, September 25, 1805 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - John Smith to Col. John Preston in Montgomery City; Requests Smith's wife's part of the estate of her late grandfather; Fayette County, Kentucky, December 21, 1805 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - John Lewis to Gen. John Preston at Horseshoe; Introduces Mr. Piersh[?], a Russian botanist on a botanical expedition, August 4, 1806 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - List of taxable property owned by John Preston in Botetourt County; Signed by William Walker, March 10, 1807 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Thomas Preston to "Dear Brother," Gen. John Preston, in Montgomery County; Concerns John Preston's support for Thomas's schooling at Washington Academy, includes a request for additional funds; Washington Academy, April 11, 1807 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - John Preston to Lt. Col. Henry Bowyer; Contains division orders, second regiment of Virginia Cavalry, July 30, 1807 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Samuel Coleman to Maj. Gen. John Preston; Order concerning state's quota of militia; Adjutant General's Office, Richmond, August 18, 1807 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - George Pury to Gen. John Preston in Montgomery City; Concerns Pury's receipt of a subpoena from Preston and a business deal between Pury and Major Shiffy; Wythe County, October 14, 1807 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Francis Preston to "Dear Brother," Gen. John Preston, in Montgomery County; Refers to Mr. King hiring Gen. Preston's Negroes; a trip to Smithfield; recent elections; Abingdon, February 26, 1808. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - John Radford to [his brother-in-law Gen. John Preston at Horseshoe Bottom, Montgomery County; Concerns his move to Ohio and acquisition of land there; Refers to bringing a slave woman with him and paying his mother $300 for her; Frankfort, July 14, 1808 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Nathaniel Hart to Gen. John Preston in Richmond; Refers to a debt to be paid in horses; Spring Hill [Kentucky], August 18, 1809 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Gen. John Preston to John Champ at Horseshoe Bottom' Includes instructions for Champ as overseer at Horseshoe Bottom; Richmond, January 9, 1810 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Godfrey Brooks to "Master," Gen. John Preston, in Richmond; Reports on affairs at Greenfield; Greenfield, April 20, 1810 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - James Breckenridge to [his cousin] Gen. John Preston in Richmond; Refers to Col. [Nicholas?] visiting the springs in the summer; includes a list of accounts as a postscript; Fincastle, May 19, 1810 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Carlton Radford to [his brother-in-law] Gen. John Preston in Richmond; Asks for money for college expenses; Washington Academy, May 27, 1810 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Promissory note for a sum to be paid for a slave; Signed Charles Taylor and J. Preston, June 9, 1810 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Francis Preston to [his brother] Gen. John Preston in Richmond; Encloses a power of attorney from William Trigg, executor of William King; concerns various law suits against Trigg and King; Abington, November 10, 1810 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Carlton T. Radford to [his brother-in-law] Gen. John Preston in Richmond; Reports on problems with the hemp harvest at Horseshoe; Abingdon, November 27, 1810 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - William Temple to Gen. J. Preston; Requests the return of a promissory note for the sum of $250, December 28, 1810 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Francis Preston to "Dear Brother," Gen. John Preston; Tells of a trip to Horseshoe to check on John Preston's farm; Mr. Champ's difficulties with the slaves; hiring a new person to help Champ; Wythe Courthouse, Janaury 17, 1811 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Moses Jackson to Gen. J. Preston; Requests that Preston intercede on his behalf with the authorities, gaining his freedom from jail; Richmond, April 2, 1811 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Susan McDowell to [her uncle], Gen. John Preston in Richmond; Congratulates him on his marriage to Mrs. Mayo; refers to Susan's visit to Staunton; Cherry Grove, May 14, 1811 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Gen. John Preston to "My dear Son," William R. Preston in Rockbridge; Requests that William return home, taking leave of his aunt, uncle, and cousins on the best of terms to begin attending Mr. Crutchfield's school in Bath County; Richmond, May 16, 1811 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Thomas Preston to "Dear Sir" [W. Preston Smith?] at the Treasury Office in Richmond; Concerns a note due at the bank, Lexington; On the same sheet: J. Preston to "Dear Preston" [W. Preston Smith]; Concerns a coming trip to Hot Springs because of rheumatic pain, July 17, 1811 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Mathias Lane to Gen. J. Preston in Richmond; Concerns squatters burning timber and selling the ashes on Preston's land in Kentucky; requests a power of attorney to remove the squatters; Glasgow, Kentucky, August 5, 1811 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - James Preston to "Dear Brother," Gen. John Preston in Richmond; Concerns the purchase of a piece of property, for which he requests payment; Smithfield, October 27, 1811 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - "Extract from H. Crutchfield's Books, requested by General Preston, in Order to know precisely the Expense of his three sons for one year;" Costs of John Preston's sons to go to school; lists tuition, board, lodging, shoes, clothing, etc.,, 1811-1812 (Box 2, Folder 20a)
  - Promissory note to Robert Gamble; Signed J. Preston, January 14, 1812 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - William R. Preston to "Dear Father," Gen. John Preston in Richmond; Concerns studies at Mr. Crutchfield's school; requests $5.00; Bath County, January 16, 1812 (Oversize 1)
  - Thomas Preston to "Dear Brother," Gen. John Preston in Richmond; Concerns a piece of property for sale; military promotions; Lexington, February 16, 1812 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Bill (and receipt) to John and Joseph Boyce.; Treasury Office, Richmond, June 20, 1812 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Cornelius Brown to Gen. John Preston in Richmond; Reports on affairs at Horseshoe Bottom; Horseshoe Bottom, July 11, 1812 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Gr. Smith to Gen. John Preston in Richmond; Fragment, July 15, 1812 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Elizabeth Ann Cabell Preston to [her husband], Gen. John Preston in Richmond; Concerns family and farming matters, September 22, 1812 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - William Preston and John Preston to "Dear Father," Gen. John Preston in Richmond; Lysander Smith to "Dear Cousin," Gen. John Preston [3 letters on 1 sheet]; Relate happenings at Mr. Crutchfield's school; Bath County, October 1, 1812 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Gen. John Preston to [his son] Whitley Preston at Horsehoe bottom, Montgomery County; Concerns Whitley's staying with his father during the winter; Richmond, November 9, 1812 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Gen. John Preston to [his son] Whitley Preston at Horseshoe Bottom, Montgomery County; Concerns farming affairs at Horseshoe Bottom; requests that Whitley come to Richmond to see the General Assembly; Richmond, December 4, 1812 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Bill to General Preston for coal; Signed John Potts, December 1812 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Received of Minor Carey, a load of coal; Signed J. Preston; Richmond, December 15, 1812 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Draft of a letter [from John Preston?] to an unspecified party; Concerns problems with a requested loan of public funds; Richmond, March 26, 1813 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - John Brockenbough [president, Bank of Virginia] to John Preston and Samuel Shepard; Concerns a loan for the Commonwealth of Virginia, June 4, 1813 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Promissory note to James McDowell [Moffatt?]; Signed J. Preston and James McDowell, September 21, 1813 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Memorandum of property at the Lower Horseshoe Bottom; Includes slaves, livestock, farm implements, November 30, 1813 (Oversize 1)
  - Memorandum of property at the Upper Horseshoe Bottom; Includes slaves, livestock, farm implements, November 30, 1813 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Whitley Preston to "Dear Father," Gen. John Preston, in Richmond; Refers to collecting a debt for his father from Mr. Edmundson, driving hogs and other farming affairs; Greenfield, January 3, 1814 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - William Radford to [his brother-in-law] Gen. John Preston in Richmond; Introduces Samuel Harrison, a merchant whose business has brought him to Richmond. Lynchburg, June 1, 1814 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Account of Gen. John Preston with D. Madison, June 1814 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Thomas Arthur to Gen. John Preston in Richmond; Concerns property Arthur wishes to buy from Preston, November 26, 1814 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Eliza Preston to "My Dear Papa," Gen. John Preston, in Richmond; Reports on Eliza's daily activities; Montgomery County, December 11, 1814 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - John B. Preston to "Dear Father," Gen. John Preston, in Richmond. Reports on school; requests clothes. Hanover County,, Febraury 26, 1815. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Francis Preston to "Dear Brother," Gen. John Preston, at Horseshoe, Montgomery County; Refers to procuring salt kettles; plaster production; the difficulty of getting white labor; Abingdon, August 30, 1815 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Bill to [John Preston?] for harness and coal; Signed Harmon Sifford, September 1, 1815 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Isaac Preston to "My Dear Uncle," Gen. John. Preston; Refers to problems with the title to a piece of property in New Market; a dinner ball given to honor Gen. Jackson; Isaac's planned move to New Orleans; Abingdon, October 26, 1815 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Francis Preston to "Dear Brother," Gen. John Preston; Concerns a loan Gen. Preston was to secure from the Bank of Virginia for Francis Preston; crops and holdings in Kentucky, October 26, 1815 (Box 2, Folder 29)